<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CSE</string>
    <string name="dev">Developer: Nannigalaxy</string>
    <string name="ver">Version: 1.0(beta)</string>
    <string name="email">Email: nannigalaxy25@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="credits">Open Source Library Credits:</string>
    <string name="epanel">ExpansionPanel by Florent37</string>


    <string name="events">Events and Workshops</string>
    <string name="syllb">Syllabus</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="qp">Question Papers</string>
    <string name="class_act">Class</string>
    <string name="notes">Notes</string>


    <string name="sem5">5th Semester</string>

    <string name="cs51">Management and Entrepreneurship for IT Industry</string>
    <string name="cs52">Computer Networks</string>
    <string name="cs53">Database Management System</string>
    <string name="cs54">Automata Theory and Computability</string>
    <string name="cs553">Advanced Java and J2EE</string>
    <string name="cs552">Introduction to Software Testing</string>
    <string name="cs562">Artificial Intelligence</string>

    <string name="csl57">Computer Network Laboratory</string>
    <string name="csl58">DBMS Laboratory with Mini Project</string>
    <string name="core">Core</string>
    <string name="elective">Professional Elective</string>
    <string name="openelect">Open Elective</string>
    <string name="lab">Laboratory</string>
    <string name="man">Manual</string>

    <string name="crd4">Credit: 04</string>
    <string name="crd3">Credit: 03</string>
    <string name="crd2">Credit: 02</string>


    <string name="cs51_content">

        \n<b>Module 1:</b> \n

        Introduction - Meaning, nature and characteristics of management, scope and
Functional areas of management, goals of management, levels of management,
brief overview of evolution of management theories,. Planning- Nature,
importance, types of plans, steps in planning, Organizing- nature and purpose,
types of Organization, Staffing- meaning, process of recruitment and selection.

        \n\n
        <b>Module 2:</b> \n

        Directing and controlling- meaning and nature of directing, leadership styles,
motivation Theories, Communication- Meaning and importance, Coordination-
meaning and importance, Controlling- meaning, steps in controlling, methods of
establishing control.

        \n\n
        <b>Module 3:</b> \n

Entrepreneur – meaning of entrepreneur, characteristics of entrepreneurs, classification and types of entrepreneurs, various stages in entrepreneurial
process, role of entrepreneurs in economic development, entrepreneurship in
India and barriers to entrepreneurship. Identification of business opportunities,
market feasibility study, technical feasibility study, financial feasibility study and
social feasibility study.

\n\n
        <b>Module 4:</b> \n

Preparation of project and ERP - meaning of project, project identification,
project selection, project report, need and significance of project report, contents,
formulation, guidelines by planning commission for project report, Enterprise
Resource Planning: Meaning and Importance- ERP and Functional areas of
Management – Marketing / Sales- Supply Chain Management – Finance and
Accounting – Human Resources – Types of reports and methods of report
generation

        \n\n
        <b>Module 5:</b> \n

Micro and Small Enterprises: Definition of micro and small enterprises,
characteristics and advantages of micro and small enterprises, steps in establishing
micro and small enterprises, Government of India indusial policy 2007 on micro and
small enterprises, case study (Microsoft), Case study(Captain G R Gopinath),case
study (N R Narayana Murthy &amp; Infosys), Institutional support: MSME-DI, NSIC,
SIDBI, KIADB, KSSIDC, TECSOK, KSFC, DIC and District level single window
agency, Introduction to IPR.

        \n\n

        <b>Text Books:</b>\n
1. Principles of Management -P. C. Tripathi, P. N. Reddy; Tata McGraw Hill, 4th / 6th
Edition, 2010.\n
2. Dynamics of Entrepreneurial Development &amp; Management -Vasant Desai Himalaya
Publishing House.\n
3. Entrepreneurship Development -Small Business Enterprises -Poornima M
Charantimath Pearson Education – 2006.\n
4. Management and Entrepreneurship - Kanishka Bedi- Oxford University Press-2017\n\n
        <b>Reference Books:</b>\n
1. Management Fundamentals -Concepts, Application, Skill Development Robert Lusier
– Thomson.\n
2. Entrepreneurship Development -S S Khanka -S Chand &amp; Co.\n
3. Management -Stephen Robbins -Pearson Education /PHI -17th Edition, 2003\n\n


</string>


    <string name="cs52_content">
        \n<b>Module 1:</b>\n
"Application Layer: Principles of Network Applications: Network Application
Architectures, Processes Communicating, Transport Services Available to
Applications, Transport Services Provided by the Internet, Application-Layer
Protocols. The Web and HTTP: Overview of HTTP, Non-persistent and
Persistent Connections, HTTP Message Format, User-Server Interaction:
Cookies, Web Caching, The Conditional GET, File Transfer: FTP Commands &amp;
Replies, Electronic Mail in the Internet: SMTP, Comparison with HTTP, Mail
Message Format, Mail Access Protocols, DNS; The Internet's Directory Service:
Services Provided by DNS, Overview of How DNS Works, DNS Records and
Messages, Peer-to-Peer Applications: P2P File Distribution, Distributed Hash
Tables, Socket Programming: creating
 Network Applications: Socket
Programming with UDP, Socket Programming with TCP.
"

        \n\n
        <b>Module 2:</b> \n

       Transport Layer : Introduction and Transport-Layer Services: Relationship
Between Transport and Network Layers, Overview of the Transport Layer in the
Internet, Multiplexing and Demultiplexing: Connectionless Transport: UDP,UDP
Segment Structure, UDP Checksum, Principles of Reliable Data Transfer:
Building a Reliable Data Transfer Protocol, Pipelined Reliable Data Transfer
Protocols, Go-Back-N, Selective repeat, Connection-Oriented Transport TCP:
The TCP Connection, TCP Segment Structure, Round-Trip Time Estimation and
Timeout, Reliable Data Transfer, Flow Control, TCP Connection Management,
Principles of Congestion Control: The Causes and the Costs of Congestion,
Approaches to Congestion Control, Network-assisted congestion-control
example, ATM ABR Congestion control, TCP Congestion Control: Fairness.


        \n\n
        <b>Module 3:</b> \n
"The Network layer: What's Inside a Router?: Input Processing, Switching,
Output Processing, Where Does Queuing Occur? Routing control plane, IPv6,A
Brief foray into IP Security, Routing Algorithms: The Link-State (LS) Routing
Algorithm, The Distance-Vector (DV) Routing Algorithm, Hierarchical Routing,
Routing in the Internet, Intra-AS Routing in the Internet: RIP, Intra-AS Routing
in the Internet: OSPF, Inter/AS Routing: BGP, Broadcast Routing Algorithms
and Multicast.
"

\n\n
        <b>Module 4:</b> \n
Wireless and Mobile Networks: Cellular Internet Access: An Overview of
Cellular Network Architecture, 3G Cellular Data Networks: Extending the
Internet to Cellular subscribers, On to 4G:LTE,Mobility management: Principles,
Addressing, Routing to a mobile node, Mobile IP, Managing mobility in cellular
Networks, Routing calls to a Mobile user, Handoffs in GSM, Wireless and
Mobility: Impact on Higher-layer protocols.


        \n\n
        <b>Module 5:</b> \n
Multimedia Networking: Properties of video, properties of Audio, Types of
multimedia Network Applications, Streaming stored video: UDP Streaming,
HTTP Streaming, Adaptive streaming and DASH, content distribution Networks,
case studies: Netflix, You Tube and Kankan.
Network Support for Multimedia: Dimensioning Best-Effort Networks,
Providing Multiple Classes of Service, Diffserv, Per-Connection Quality-of-
Service (QoS) Guarantees: Resource Reservation and Call Admission

        \n\n

        <b>Text Books:</b>\n
1. James F Kurose and Keith W Ross, Computer Networking, A Top-Down Approach,
Sixth edition, Pearson,2017 .\n\n
        <b>Reference Books:</b>\n
1. Behrouz A Forouzan, Data and Communications and Networking, Fifth Edition,
McGraw Hill, Indian Edition\n
2. Larry L Peterson and Brusce S Davie, Computer Networks, fifth edition, ELSEVIER\n
3. Andrew S Tanenbaum, Computer Networks, fifth edition, Pearson\n
4. Mayank Dave, Computer Networks, Second edition, Cengage Learning
\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="cs53_content">        \n<b>Module 1:</b> \n

Introduction to Databases: Introduction, Characteristics of database approach,
Advantages of using the DBMS approach, History of database applications.
Overview of Database Languages and Architectures: Data Models, Schemas,
and Instances. Three schema architecture and data independence, database
languages, and interfaces, The Database System environment. Conceptual Data
Modelling using Entities and Relationships: Entity types, Entity sets,
attributes, roles, and structural constraints, Weak entity types, ER diagrams,
examples, Specialization and Generalization.



        \n\n
        <b>Module 2:</b> \n

Relational Model: Relational Model Concepts, Relational Model Constraints
and relational database schemas, Update operations, transactions, and dealing
with constraint violations. Relational Algebra: Unary and Binary relational
operations, additional relational operations (aggregate, grouping, etc.) Examples
of Queries in relational algebra. Mapping Conceptual Design into a Logical
Design: Relational Database Design using ER-to-Relational mapping. SQL:
SQL data definition and data types, specifying constraints in SQL, retrieval
queries in SQL, INSERT, DELETE, and UPDATE statements in SQL,
Additional features of SQL.



        \n\n
        <b>Module 3:</b> \n

SQL : Advances Queries: More complex SQL retrieval queries, Specifying
constraints as assertions and action triggers, Views in SQL, Schema change
statements in SQL. Database Application Development: Accessing databases
from applications, An introduction to JDBC, JDBC classes and interfaces, SQLJ,
Stored procedures, Case study: The internet Bookshop. Internet Applications:
The three-Tier application architecture, The presentation layer, The Middle Tier


\n\n
        <b>Module 4:</b> \n
Normalization: Database Design Theory – Introduction to Normalization using
Functional and Multivalued Dependencies: Informal design guidelines for
relation schema, Functional Dependencies, Normal Forms based on Primary
Keys, Second and Third Normal Forms, Boyce-Codd Normal Form, Multivalued
Dependency and Fourth Normal Form, Join Dependencies and Fifth Normal
Form. Normalization Algorithms: Inference Rules, Equivalence, and Minimal
Cover, Properties of Relational Decompositions, Algorithms for Relational
Database Schema Design, Nulls, Dangling tuples, and alternate Relational
Designs, Further discussion of Multivalued dependencies and 4NF, Other
dependencies and Normal Forms


        \n\n
        <b>Module 5:</b> \n
Transaction Processing: Introduction to Transaction Processing, Transaction
and System concepts, Desirable properties of Transactions, Characterizing
schedules based on recoverability, Characterizing schedules based on
Serializability, Transaction support in SQL. Concurrency Control in
Databases: Two-phase locking techniques for Concurrency control, Concurrency
control based on Timestamp ordering, Multiversion Concurrency control
techniques, Validation Concurrency control techniques, Granularity of Data
items and Multiple Granularity Locking. Introduction to Database Recovery
Protocols: Recovery Concepts, NO-UNDO/REDO recovery based on Deferred
update, Recovery techniques based on immediate update, Shadow paging,
Database backup and recovery from catastrophic failures

        \n\n

<b>Text Books:</b>       \n
1. Database systems Models, Languages, Design and Application Programming,
RamezElmasri and Shamkant B. Navathe, 7th Edition, 2017, Pearson.\n
2. Database management systems, Ramakrishnan, and Gehrke, 3 Edition, 2014,
McGraw Hill\n\n
        <b>Reference Books:</b>\n
1. Silberschatz Korth and Sudharshan, Database System Concepts, 6th Edition, Mc-
GrawHill, 2013.\n
2. Coronel, Morris, and Rob, Database Principles Fundamentals of Design,
Implementation and Management, Cengage Learning 2012.\n\n

    </string>
    <string name="cs54_content">       \n<b>Module 1:</b> \n
Why study the Theory of Computation, Languages and Strings: Strings,
Languages. A Language Hierarchy, Computation, Finite State Machines
(FSM): Deterministic FSM, Regular languages, Designing FSM,
Nondeterministic FSMs, From FSMs to Operational Systems, Simulators for
FSMs, Minimizing FSMs, Canonical form of Regular languages, Finite State
Transducers, Bidirectional Transducers.

        \n\n
        <b>Module 2:</b> \n

Regular Expressions (RE): what is a RE?, Kleene’s theorem, Applications of
REs, Manipulating and Simplifying REs. Regular Grammars: Definition,
Regular Grammars and Regular languages. Regular Languages (RL) and Non-
regular Languages: How many RLs, To show that a language is regular, Closure
properties of RLs, to show some languages are not RLs.

        \n\n
        <b>Module 3:</b> \n
Context-Free Grammars(CFG): Introduction to Rewrite Systems and Grammars,
CFGs and languages, designing CFGs, simplifying CFGs, proving that a
Grammar is correct, Derivation and Parse trees, Ambiguity, Normal Forms.
Pushdown Automata (PDA): Definition of non-deterministic PDA, Deterministic
and Non-deterministic PDAs, Non-determinism and Halting, alternative
equivalent definitions of a PDA, alternatives that are not equivalent to PDA.



\n\n
        <b>Module 4:</b> \n
Context-Free and Non-Context-Free Languages: Where do the Context-Free
Languages(CFL) fit, Showing a language is context-free, Pumping theorem for
CFL, Important closure properties of CFLs, Deterministic CFLs. Algorithms and
Decision Procedures for CFLs: Decidable questions, Un-decidable questions.
Turing Machine: Turing machine model, Representation, Language acceptability
by TM, design of TM, Techniques for TM construction.


        \n\n
        <b>Module 5:</b> \n
Variants of Turing Machines (TM), The model of Linear Bounded automata:
Decidability: Definition of an algorithm, decidability, decidable languages,
Undecidable languages, halting problem of TM, Post correspondence problem.
Complexity: Growth rate of functions, the classes of P and NP, Quantum
Computation: quantum computers, Church-Turing thesis.

        \n\n


        <b>Text Books:</b>\n
1. Elaine Rich, Automata, Computability and Complexity, 1st Edition, Pearson
Education,2012/2013\n
2. K L P Mishra, N Chandrasekaran , 3rd Edition, Theory of Computer Science, PhI, 2012.\n\n
        <b>Reference Books:</b>\n
1. John E Hopcroft, Rajeev Motwani, Jeffery D Ullman, Introduction to AutomataTheory,
Languages, and Computation, 3rd Edition, Pearson Education, 2013\n
2. Michael Sipser : Introduction to the Theory of Computation, 3rd edition, Cengage
learning,2013\n
3. John C Martin, Introduction to Languages and The Theory of Computation, 3rd Edition,
Tata McGraw –Hill Publishing Company Limited, 2013\n
4. Peter Linz, “An Introduction to Formal Languages and Automata”, 3rd Edition, Narosa
Publishers, 1998\n
5. Basavaraj S. Anami, Karibasappa K G, Formal Languages and Automata theory, Wiley
India, 2012\n
6. C K Nagpal, Formal Languages and Automata Theory, Oxford University press, 2012.\n\n

        </string>
    <string name="cs552_content">

        \n<b>Module 1:</b> \n

Basics of Software Testing: Basic definitions, Software Quality , Requirements,
Behaviour and Correctness, Correctness versus Reliability, Testing and
Debugging, Test cases, Insights from a Venn diagram, Identifying test cases,
Test-generation Strategies, Test Metrics, Error and fault taxonomies , Levels of
testing, Testing and Verification, Static Testing.

        \n\n
        <b>Module 2:</b> \n

Problem Statements: Generalized pseudo code, the triangle problem, the
NextDate function, the commission problem, the SATM (Simple Automatic
Teller Machine) problem, the currency converter, Saturn windshield wiper
Functional Testing: Boundary value analysis, Robustness testing, Worst-case
testing, Robust Worst testing for triangle problem, NextDate problem and
commission problem, Equivalence classes, Equivalence test cases for the triangle
problem, NextDate function, and the commission problem, Guidelines and
observations, Decision tables, Test cases for the triangle problem, NextDate
function, and the commission problem, Guidelines and observations.


        \n\n
        <b>Module 3:</b> \n
Fault Based Testing: Overview, Assumptions in fault based testing, Mutation
analysis, Fault-based adequacy criteria, Variations on mutation analysis.
Structural Testing: Overview, Statement testing, Branch testing, Condition
testing, Path testing: DD paths, Test coverage metrics, Basis path testing,
guidelines and observations, Data –Flow testing: Definition-Use testing, Slice-
based testing, Guidelines and observations.




\n\n
        <b>Module 4:</b> \n
Test Execution: Overview of test execution, from test case specification to test
cases, Scaffolding, Generic versus specific scaffolding, Test oracles, Self-checks
as oracles, Capture and replay Process Framework :Basic principles:
Sensitivity, redundancy, restriction, partition, visibility, Feedback, the quality
process, Planning and monitoring, Quality goals, Dependability properties
,Analysis Testing, Improving the process, Organizational factors.
Planning and Monitoring the Process: Quality and process, Test and analysis
strategies and plans, Risk planning, monitoring the process, Improving the
process, the quality team.


        \n\n
        <b>Module 5:</b> \n
Integration and Component-Based Software Testing: Overview, Integration
testing strategies, Testing components and assemblies. System, Acceptance and
Regression Testing: Overview, System testing, Acceptance testing, Usability,
Regression testing, Regression test selection techniques, Test case prioritization
and selective execution. Levels of Testing, Integration Testing: Traditional
view of testing levels, Alternative life-cycle models, The SATM system,
Separating integration and system testing, A closer look at the SATM system,
Decomposition-based, call graph-based, Path-based integrations.
        \n\n

        <b>Text Books:</b>\n
1. Paul C. Jorgensen: Software Testing, A Craftsman’s Approach, 3rd Edition, Auerbach
Publications, 2008.\n
2. Mauro Pezze, Michal Young: Software Testing and Analysis – Process, Principles and
Techniques, Wiley India, 2009.\n
3. Aditya P Mathur: Foundations of Software Testing, Pearson Education, 2008.\n\n
        <b>Reference Books:</b>\n
1. Software testing Principles and Practices – Gopalaswamy Ramesh, Srinivasan Desikan, 2nd Edition, Pearson, 2007.\n
2. Software Testing – Ron Patton, 2nd edition, Pearson Education, 2004.\n
3. The Craft of Software Testing – Brian Marrick, Pearson Education, 1995.\n
4. Anirban Basu, Software Quality Assurance, Testing and Metrics, PHI, 2015\n
5. Naresh Chauhan, Software Testing, Oxford University press.\n\n


    </string>
    <string name="cs553_content">
        \n<b>Module 1:</b> \n
Enumerations, Autoboxing and Annotations(metadata): Enumerations,
Enumeration fundamentals, the values() and valueOf() Methods, java
enumerations are class types, enumerations Inherits Enum, example, type
wrappers, Autoboxing, Autoboxing and Methods, Autoboxing/Unboxing occurs
in Expressions, Autoboxing/Unboxing, Boolean and character values,
Autoboxing/Unboxing helps prevent errors, A word of Warning. Annotations,
Annotation basics, specifying retention policy, Obtaining Annotations at run
time by use of reflection, Annotated element Interface, Using Default values,
Marker Annotations, Single Member annotations, Built-In annotations.

        \n\n
        <b>Module 2:</b> \n

The collections and Framework: Collections Overview, Recent Changes to
Collections, The Collection Interfaces, The Collection Classes, Accessing a
collection Via an Iterator, Storing User Defined Classes in Collections, The
Random Access Interface, Working With Maps, Comparators, The Collection
Algorithms, Why Generic Collections?, The legacy Classes and Interfaces,
Parting Thoughts on Collections.


        \n\n
        <b>Module 3:</b> \n
String Handling :The String Constructors, String Length, Special String
Operations, String Literals, String Concatenation, String Concatenation with
Other Data Types, String Conversion and toString( ) Character Extraction,
charAt( ), getChars( ), getBytes( ) toCharArray(), String Comparison, equals( )
and equalsIgnoreCase( ), regionMatches( ) startsWith( ) and endsWith( ), equals(
) Versus == , compareTo( ) Searching Strings, Modifying a String, substring( ),
concat( ), replace( ), trim( ), Data Conversion Using valueOf( ), Changing the
Case of Characters Within a String, Additional String Methods, StringBuffer ,
StringBuffer Constructors, length( ) and capacity( ), ensureCapacity( ),
setLength( ), charAt( ) and setCharAt( ), getChars( ),append( ), insert( ), reverse(
), delete( ) and deleteCharAt( ), replace( ), substring( ), Additional StringBuffer
Methods, StringBuilder

\n\n
        <b>Module 4:</b> \n
Background; The Life Cycle of a Servlet; Using Tomcat for Servlet
Development; A simple Servlet; The Servlet API; The Javax.servlet Package;
Reading Servlet Parameter; The Javax.servlet.http package; Handling HTTP
Requests and Responses; Using Cookies; Session Tracking. Java Server Pages
(JSP): JSP, JSP Tags, Tomcat, Request String, User Sessions, Cookies, Session
Objects


        \n\n
        <b>Module 5:</b> \n
The Concept of JDBC; JDBC Driver Types; JDBC Packages; A Brief Overview
of the JDBC process; Database Connection; Associating the JDBC/ODBC
Bridge with the Database; Statement Objects; ResultSet; Transaction Processing;
Metadata, Data types; Exceptions.
        \n\n

        <b>Text Books:</b>\n

1. Herbert Schildt: JAVA the Complete Reference, 7th/9th Edition, Tata McGraw Hill,
2007.\n
2. Jim Keogh: J2EE-TheCompleteReference, McGraw Hill, 2007.\n\n
        <b>Reference Books:</b>\n

1. Y. Daniel Liang: Introduction to JAVA Programming, 7th Edition, Pearson Education,
2007.\n
2. Stephanie Bodoff et al: The J2EE Tutorial, 2nd Edition, Pearson Education,2004.\n
3. Uttam K Roy, Advanced JAVA programming, Oxford University press, 2015.\n\n

        </string>
    <string name="cs562_content"> \n<b>Module 1:</b> \n
What is artificial intelligence?, Problems, Problem Spaces and search, Heuristic
search technique


        \n\n
        <b>Module 2:</b> \n
Knowledge Representation Issues, Using Predicate Logic, Representing
knowledge using Rules,


        \n\n
        <b>Module 3:</b> \n
Symbolic Reasoning under Uncertainty, Statistical reasoning, Weak Slot and
Filter Structures.


\n\n
        <b>Module 4:</b> \n
Strong slot-and-filler structures, Game Playing.



        \n\n
        <b>Module 5:</b> \n
Natural Language Processing, Learning, Expert Systems.
        \n\n

        <b>Text Books:</b>\n
1. E. Rich , K. Knight &amp; S. B. Nair - Artificial Intelligence, 3/e, McGraw Hill.\n\n
        <b>Reference Books:</b>\n
1. Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach, Stuart Rusell, Peter Norving, Pearson
Education 2nd Edition.\n\n

</string>
    <string name="csl57_content"><b>Description:</b>\n
For the experiments below modify the topology and parameters set for the experiment and
take multiple rounds of reading and analyze the results available in log files. Plot necessary
graphs and conclude. Use NS2/NS3.\n\n
<b>Lab Experiments:</b>\n
        <b>PART A</b>\n
1. Implement three nodes point – to – point network with duplex links between them.
Set the queue size, vary the bandwidth and find the number of packets dropped.\n
2. Implement transmission of ping messages/trace route over a network topology
consisting of 6 nodes and find the number of packets dropped due to congestion.\n
3. Implement an Ethernet LAN using n nodes and set multiple traffic nodes and plot
congestion window for different source / destination.\n
4. Implement simple ESS and with transmitting nodes in wire-less LAN by simulation
and determine the performance with respect to transmission of packets.\n
5. Implement and study the performance of GSM on NS2/NS3 (Using MAC layer) or
equivalent environment.\n
6. Implement and study the performance of CDMA on NS2/NS3 (Using stack called
Call net) or equivalent environment.\n\n
<b>PART B</b>\n
Implement the following in Java:\n
7. Write a program for error detecting code using CRC-CCITT (16- bits).\n
8. Write a program to find the shortest path between vertices using bellman-ford
algorithm.\n
9. Using TCP/IP sockets, write a client – server program to make the client send the file
name and to make the server send back the contents of the requested file if present.\n
10. Write a program on datagram socket for client/server to display the messages on
client side, typed at the server side.\n
11. Write a program for simple RSA algorithm to encrypt and decrypt the data.\n
12. Write a program for congestion control using leaky bucket algorithm.\n

        <b>Conduction of Practical Examination:</b>\n
1. All laboratory experiments are to be included for practical examination.\n
2. Students are allowed to pick one experiment from part A and part B with lot.\n
3. Strictly follow the instructions as printed on the cover page of answer script.\n
4. Marks distribution: Procedure + Conduction + Viva: 80\n
Part A: 10+25+5
 =40\n
Part B: 10+25+5
 =40\n
5. Change of experiment is allowed only once and marks allotted to the procedure part to be
made zero.\n\n
</string>
    <string name="csl58_content">\n<b>Description:</b>\n
        <b>PART-A: SQL Programming (Max. Exam Mks. 50)</b>\n
• Design, develop, and implement the specified queries for the following problems
using Oracle, MySQL, MS SQL Server, or any other DBMS under
LINUX/Windows environment.\n
• Create Schema and insert at least 5 records for each table. Add appropriate
database constraints.\n
        <b>PART-B: Mini Project (Max. Exam Mks. 30)</b>
• Use Java, C#, PHP, Python, or any other similar front-end tool.\n
        All applications must be demonstrated on desktop/laptop as a stand-alone or web
based application (Mobile apps on Android/IOS are not permitted.)\n\n
        <b>Lab Experiments:</b>\n
        <b>Part A: SQL Programming</b>\n
1) Consider the following schema for a Library Database:\n
BOOK(Book_id, Title, Publisher_Name, Pub_Year)\n
BOOK_AUTHORS(Book_id, Author_Name)\n
PUBLISHER(Name, Address, Phone)\n
BOOK_COPIES(Book_id, Branch_id, No-of_Copies)\n
BOOK_LENDING(Book_id, Branch_id, Card_No, Date_Out, Due_Date)\n
LIBRARY_BRANCH(Branch_id, Branch_Name, Address)\n
Write SQL queries to\n
1. Retrieve details of all books in the library – id, title, name of publisher,
authors, number of copies in each branch, etc.\n
2. Get the particulars of borrowers who have borrowed more than 3 books, but
from Jan 2017 to Jun 2017.\n
3. Delete a book in BOOK table. Update the contents of other tables to reflect
this data manipulation operation.\n
4. Partition the BOOK table based on year of publication. Demonstrate its
working with a simple query.\n
5. Create a view of all books and its number of copies that are currently
available in the Library.\n\n
2) Consider the following schema for Order Database:\n
SALESMAN(Salesman_id, Name, City, Commission)\n
CUSTOMER(Customer_id, Cust_Name, City, Grade, Salesman_id)\n
ORDERS(Ord_No, Purchase_Amt, Ord_Date, Customer_id, Salesman_id)\n
Write SQL queries to\n
1. Count the customers with grades above Bangalore’s average.\n
2. Find the name and numbers of all salesman who had more than one customer.\n
3. List all the salesman and indicate those who have and don’t have customers in
their cities (Use UNION operation.)\n
4. Create a view that finds the salesman who has the customer with the highest
order of a day.\n
5. Demonstrate the DELETE operation by removing salesman with id 1000. All
his orders must also be deleted.\n\n
3) Consider the schema for Movie Database:\n
ACTOR(Act_id, Act_Name, Act_Gender)\n
DIRECTOR(Dir_id, Dir_Name, Dir_Phone)\n
MOVIES(Mov_id, Mov_Title, Mov_Year, Mov_Lang, Dir_id)\n
MOVIE_CAST(Act_id, Mov_id, Role)\n
RATING(Mov_id, Rev_Stars)\n
Write SQL queries to\n
1. List the titles of all movies directed by ‘Hitchcock’.\n
2. Find the movie names where one or more actors acted in two or more movies.\n
3. List all actors who acted in a movie before 2000 and also in a movie after
2015 (use JOIN operation).\n
4. Find the title of movies and number of stars for each movie that has at least
one rating and find the highest number of stars that movie received. Sort the
result by movie title.\n
5. Update rating of all movies directed by ‘Steven Spielberg’ to 5.\n\n
4) Consider the schema for College Database:\n
STUDENT(USN, SName, Address, Phone, Gender)\n
SEMSEC(SSID, Sem, Sec)\n
CLASS(USN, SSID)\n
SUBJECT(Subcode, Title, Sem, Credits)\n
IAMARKS(USN, Subcode, SSID, Test1, Test2, Test3, FinalIA)\n
Write SQL queries to\n
1. List all the student details studying in fourth semester ‘C’ section.\n
2. Compute the total number of male and female students in each semester and in
each section.\n
3. Create a view of Test1 marks of student USN ‘1BI15CS101’ in all subjects.\n
4. Calculate the FinalIA (average of best two test marks) and update the
corresponding table for all students.\n
5. Categorize students based on the following criterion:\n
If FinalIA = 17 to 20 then CAT = ‘Outstanding’\n
If FinalIA = 12 to 16 then CAT = ‘Average’\n
If FinalIA &lt; 12 then CAT = ‘Weak’\n
Give these details only for 8th semester A, B, and C section students.\n\n
5) Consider the schema for Company Database:\n
EMPLOYEE(SSN, Name, Address, Sex, Salary, SuperSSN, DNo)\n
DEPARTMENT(DNo, DName, MgrSSN, MgrStartDate)\n
DLOCATION(DNo,DLoc)\n
PROJECT(PNo, PName, PLocation, DNo)\n
WORKS_ON(SSN, PNo, Hours)\n
Write SQL queries to\n
1. Make a list of all project numbers for projects that involve an employee
whose last name is ‘Scott’, either as a worker or as a manager of the
department that controls the project.\n
2. Show the resulting salaries if every employee working on the ‘IoT’ project is
given a 10 percent raise.\n
3. Find the sum of the salaries of all employees of the ‘Accounts’ department, as
well as the maximum salary, the minimum salary, and the average salary in
this department.\n
4. Retrieve the name of each employee who works on all the projects
controlledby department number 5 (use NOT EXISTS operator).\n
5. For each department that has more than five employees, retrieve the
department number and the number of its employees who are making more
than Rs. 6,00,000.\n\n
        <b>Part B: Mini project</b>\n
• For any problem selected, write the ER Diagram, apply ER-mapping rules,
normalize the relations, and follow the application development process.\n
• Make sure that the application should have five or more tables, at least one
trigger and one stored procedure, using suitable frontend tool.\n
• Indicative areas include; health care, education, industry, transport, supply chain,
etc.\n
Course outcomes: The students should be able to:\n
• Create, Update and query on the database.\n
• Demonstrate the working of different concepts of DBMS.\n
• Implement, analyze and evaluate the project developed for an application.\n\n
        <b>Conduction of Practical Examination:</b>\n
1. All laboratory experiments from part A are to be included for practical
examination.\n
2. Mini project has to be evaluated for 30 Marks.\n
3. Report should be prepared in a standard format prescribed for project work.\n
4. Students are allowed to pick one experiment from the lot.\n
5. Strictly follow the instructions as printed on the cover page of answer script.\n
6. Marks distribution:\n
\t a) Part A: Procedure + Conduction + Viva:10 + 35 +5 =50 Marks\n
\t b) Part B: Demonstration + Report + Viva voce = 15+10+05 = 30 Marks\n
7. Change of experiment is allowed only once and marks allotted to the procedure
part to be made zero.\n\n
</string>





</resources>
